

Poorya Sheikh

Cloud DevOps Engineer

poorya.sheikh@gmail.com

+77478086640

Almaty, Kazakhstan

haikh 🔚

linkedin.com/in/poorya-sheikh

github.com/pooryasheikh ()

g.a..ea..., poor year.e.....

Experienced Cloud DevOps Engineer with 5 years combined as Cloud, and DevOps engineer, as well as Linux Systems Administrator. Solid understanding of principles of Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment, Continuous Delivery, and Cloud Implementations with demonstrated hands-on field experience. In-depth experience in AWS cloud services such as EC2, S3, EBS, ELB, Cloud Watch, Elastic IP, RDS, IAM, VPC, and Route53.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud Providers AWS, Linode, Digital Ocean, Hetzner **Databases** MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ScyllaDB

Key DBs Redis, MemcacheD **IaC** Terraform, SaltStack, Ansible, Terragrunt

Virtualization Proxmox, Ovirt Load balancers Nginx, HAproxy, Metallb, Proxysql

Message brokers RabbitMQ, Kafka Log Graylog, Loki, Datadog, ELK

Managements

Service Mesh: Istio, Linkerd, Envoy, Consul Programming Python, Shell, Lua

Monitoring Sentry, Datadog, Elastic APM, Zabbix, Container Kubernetes, Docker Swarm

Datadog, Grafana, Prometheus Orchestrations

WORK EXPERIENCES

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Evrone Team 02/2022 - Present

Evrone.com is an IT consultant Company specializing in the development of services for high-load systems.

- Achievements/Tasks

- Improved Helm chart from simple chart to umbrella chart for better version controlling between the company branches.
- Implemented FluxCD to change from push base deployment to pull base for improve continuous delivery.
- Administered CloudFlare with +6 domain for proxies DNS record to Kubernetes Nginx Ingress Controller.
- Initiated infrastructure as a code with combination of Terraform and Terragrunt for AWS cloud services such as EKS, S3, EC2, RDS, VPC, and etc.
- Migrated from private cloud provider to AWS for better managing the budget and high availability of the system.

DevOps Engineer

Arbuz Team

04/2021 - 02/2022 Almaty, Kazakhstan

Arbuz is an online supermarket which has quickly become the largest one in the country, and the favorite choice of many.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Designed an architectural diagram for applications before migrating into Public Cloud (OpenStack PS.kz) for flexible, costeffective, reliable, scalable, high-performance and secured operations.
- Designed and built a continuous integration and deployment with Helm chart in Gitlab.
- Deployed VPC with full-mesh tunnel between cloud providers.
- Migrated from Docker Swarm to Kubernetes for better handling over deployment and container horizontal auto scaling.
- Implemented Single Source of Truth as an authentication center based on FreeIPA for all internal authentication (SSH, LDAP integration, and Policy management).

Page 1 of 2

Remote

WORK EXPERIENCES

System Administrator

Kolesa Group

08/2019 - 04/2021 Almaty, Kazakhstan

Services for the placement and publication of private ads for the sale and purchase of cars, real estate, and services in Kazakhstan.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Administered more than 2500 virtual machine in Proxmox clusters in 5 data centers.
- Implemented AWX in Kubernetes, and lifted all the playbooks to the AWX.
- Used Ansible and AWX as Configuration management tools, to automate repetitive tasks, quickly deploys critical
 applications, and proactively manages change.
- Developed dynamic inventory in python for Ansible to interact with API of FreeIPAM.
- Launched intrusion detection system base on Suricata for monitoring ingress and egress traffic in every data center (multi zone).

System Administrator

RG Brands

04/2018 - 07/2019 Almaty, Kazakhstan

RG brands is a leading beverage company.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Converted ATC to VoIP for more than 500 extensions
- Designed super mesh networking of the main branch building with 25 access switches, 2 core switches, and a core router
- Administered more than 100 servers physical and virtual
- Managed Microsoft Active Directory for more than 600 users and computers
- Implemented monitoring system with Zabbix and Grafana
- Built clusters of OVirt with GlusterFS storage system

EDUCATION

Associate Degree in Information and Communication Technology
 Jahad University of Ahvaz

2009 - 2012

LANGUAGES

English Russian Persian

Professional Working Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency